Viet Danh Nguyen

Kitchener, Ontario, N2H 4H7

(226) 898-4373 | vdnguyen3012@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vietdanhnguyen/

GitHub: https://github.com/vdnguyen3012

Plum: https://secure.plum.io/p/p R5YUscRQnfAs8Hn3L Vq

PROFILE

Web Developer with 5+ years of experience in planning, developing, testing and maintaining a variety of websites in many fields such as education, eCommerce and entertainment. Researched and implemented a wide range of technologies to systems to improve performance and productivity. Proven ability in working with clients to get requirements, give solutions and tackle business issues. Hard-working, good at working under pressure, time management and be able to work individually as well as in a set of teams.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer

Netwila Applications Corp, Whitby On Canada, Part-time

Jan 2021 - Present Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- Maintain and develop websites using ReactJS
- · Analyzed, developed and implemented back end programs using Nodejs / Express, NesJS

Co-op

Web Developer

Pure Solutions International, HCM Viet Nam, Part-time

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

- Plan, develop, test, deploy, and maintain clients' applications.
- Maintain and develop websites, code, and data structure in the company.
- Implement migration of production to cloud server.
- Assist team members when needed and do peer code reviews.
- Participate in all stages of software development life cycle in Agile methodology.

Web Developer

Pure Solutions International, HCM Viet Nam, Full-time

Jul 2014 - Jan 2019

- Analyzed, developed and implemented back end programs using different programming languages Ruby / Ruby on Rails, Javascript / NodeJS or PHP / Codeigniter.
- Worked as a productive and positive team member to design, code, test, report, and debug operations.
- Researched and developed functional and technical specifications from business requirements.
- Created RESTFUL Web Services for the application components for testing purposes.
- Met regularly with business stakeholders and management to understand and refine business and functional requirements and determine project scopes and specifications.

PHP Developer

IM Group, HCM Viet Nam, Full-time

Mar 2014 - Jun 2014

• Developed, maintained, upgraded, and tested operations of the company's website.

- Worked with other coworkers to analyze, develop, and implement requirements from clients.
- Worked on front-end validation through JavaScript, Jquery, and back-end validation using validation libraries.

PHP Developer

Silkwires , HCM Viet Nam, Intership

Aug 2013 - Feb 2014

- Participated in the life cycle of developing projects, applications using Zend1 Framework.
- Ensured delivery within tight time-lines and meeting the team's expectations.
- Worked guickly and carefully to complete small edits requested by team leader.

SKILLS

Programming Skills: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, Express, ReactJS, NestJS, JavaScript, PHP,

Codeigniter, HTML, CSS, Jquery, Ajax

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis

Web Servers: Apache, Nginx

Others: Linux, Ubuntu, Git, RESTful APIs

EDUCATION

Mobile Solutions Development - Designation (Co-op)

2020 - 2021

Conestoga College, 299 Doon Valley Dr, Kitchener, ON N2G 4M4

Higher Diploma in Software Engineering

2009 - 2011

FPT Aptech, HCM VietNam